<?xml version="1.0"?>
<configuration>
	<placeholders>
		<placeholder id="template_name">SFDC2DB-account-bidirectional-sync</placeholder>
	</placeholders>
	<sections>
		<section id="use_case">
			As a Salesforce admin, I want to have my accounts synchronized between Salesforce and Database organizations.
		</section>
		<section id="considerations">
<![CDATA[
### Template overview
Let's say we want to keep Salesforce instance synchronized with Database instance. Then, the integration behavior can be summarized just with the following steps:

1. Ask Salesforce:
> *Which changes have there been since the last time I got in touch with you?*

2. For each of the updates fetched in the previous step (1.), ask Database:
> *Does the update received from Salesforce should be applied?*

3. If Database answer for the previous question (2.) is *Yes*, then *upsert* (create or update depending each particular case) Database with the belonging change

4. Repeat previous steps (1. to 3.) the other way around (using Database as source instance and Salesforce as the target one)

 Repeat *ad infinitum*:

5. Ask Salesforce:
> *Which changes have there been since the question I've made in the step 1.?*

And so on...

### Note
 This particular Anypoint Template illustrate the synchronization use case between SalesForce and a Database, thus it requires a DB instance to work.
The Anypoint Template comes packaged with a SQL script to create the DB table that uses. 
It is the user responsibility to use that script to create the table in an available schema and change the configuration accordingly.
The SQL script file can be found in [src/main/resources/account.sql] (../master/src/main/resources/account.sql)
  
  
The question for recent changes since a certain moment is nothing but a [poll inbound](http://www.mulesoft.org/documentation/display/current/Poll+Reference) with a [watermark](http://blogs.mulesoft.org/data-synchronizing-made-easy-with-mule-watermarks/) defined.
]]>
		</section>
		<section id="running_on_studio">
		<![CDATA[
Once you have imported you Anypoint Template into Anypoint Studio you need to follow these steps to run it:

+ Locate the properties file `mule.dev.properties`, in src/main/resources
+ Complete all the properties required as per the examples in the section [Properties to be configured](#propertiestobeconfigured)
+ Once that is done, right click on you Anypoint Template project folder 
+ Hover you mouse over `"Run as"`
+ Click on  `"Mule Application"`
		]]>
		</section>
		<section id="application_configuration">
		<![CDATA[
		
+ polling.frequency `10000`  
This are the milliseconds (also different time units can be used) that will run between two different checks for updates in Salesforce and Database

+ watermark.default.expression `2014-02-25T11:00:00.000Z`  
This property is an important one, as it configures what should be the start point of the synchronization.The date format accepted in SFDC Query Language is either *YYYY-MM-DDThh:mm:ss+hh:mm* or you can use Constants. [More information about Dates in SFDC][3]

### SalesForce Connector configuration
+ sfdc.username `jorge.drexler@mail.com`
+ sfdc.password `Noctiluca123`
+ sfdc.securityToken `avsfwCUl7apQs56Xq2AKi3X`
+ sfdc.url `https://login.salesforce.com/services/Soap/u/28.0`
+ sfdc.integration.user.id `005n0000000T3QkAAK`

### Database Connector configuration
+ database.url=jdbc:mysql://192.168.224.130:3306/mule?user=mule&password=mule
+ db.integration.user.id=mule@localhost

If it is required to connect to a different Database there should be provided the jar for the library and changed the value of that field in the connector.
]]>
		</section>
		<section id="api_calls">
		<![CDATA[
SalesForce imposes limits on the number of API Calls that can be made.
Therefore calculating this amount may be an important factor to
consider. Product Broadcast Template calls to the API can be
calculated using the formula:

**X / 200**

Being X the number of Products to be synchronized on each run.

The division by 200 is because, by default, Users are gathered in groups
of 200 for each Upsert API Call in the commit step. Also consider
that this calls are executed repeatedly every polling cycle.

For instance if 10 records are fetched from origin instance, then 1 api
calls to SFDC will be made ( 1).
]]>
		</section>
	</sections>
</configuration>